Never reveal your name. Never turn your back. Never surrender your heart.
The Saint is a thriller, action, romance film directed by Phillip Noyce.
Simon Templar (The Saint), is a thief for hire, whose latest job to steal the secret process for cold fusion puts him at
odds with a traitor bent on toppling the Russian government, as well as the woman who holds its secret.
Simon Templar, played by Val Kilmer.
Emma Russell, played by Elisabeth Shue.
Ivan Tretiak, played by Rade Šerbedžija.
Dr. Lev Botvin, played by Henry Goodman.
Inspector Teal, played by Alun Armstrong.
Vereshagin, played by Michael Byrne.
The Saint is a 1997 American action thriller film directed by Phillip Noyce, written by Jonathan Hensleigh and
Wesley Strick, and starring Val Kilmer in the title role, with Elisabeth Shue and Rade Šerbedžija.
The plot of the film revolves around the title character who is a high-tech thief and master of
disguise, who becomes the anti-hero while using the moniker of various saints.
He paradoxically lives in the underworld of
international industrial theft and espionage.
The film was a modest financial success with a worldwide box office of $169.4
million, rentals of $28.2 million, and continuous DVD sales.
It is loosely based on the character of Simon Templar created by Leslie Charteris in
1928 for a series of books published as "The Saint", which ran until 1983.
The Saint character has also featured in a series of Hollywood films made between 1938 and 1954, a 1940s radio series starring Vincent Price (and
others) as Templar, a popular British television series of the 1960s starring Roger Moore, and a 1970s series starring Ian Ogilvy.
The film explores themes of berlin, germany, london,
england, gas, based on novel or book, espionage.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and intense.